novelexperience.info 2019-06-16

# Privacy Policy - Novel Experience

It is Novel Experience’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect from you or which you may provide to us, in the circumstances set out below. Accordingly, we have developed this privacy policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate, disclose, safeguard and otherwise make use of your personally identifiable information (“Personal Data”).

We will only collect and use your Personal Data where:

• We have lawful grounds to do so, including to comply with our legal obligations;  
• We are  performing a contract with you forour services; and  
• We have legitimate interests in using your Personal Data and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation ((EU) 2016/679) (“GDPR”), I, Hazel Longuet, am the “data controller”. If you have any questions about this policy or about how we use your Personal Data, please contact me via my contact details at the end of this policy.

This policy is effective as of 24th May 2018. I review my privacy practices on an ongoing basis, and as such, I may change this privacy policy from time to time. Please check this page frequently to ensure you are familiar with its current content.

1\. Personal Data we collect via  our website www.novelexperience.info (the “Website”)

 _Personal Data that you provide to me_

We only collect Personal Data where you choose to interact with us on the Website in the following ways:

Activity| Types of Personal Data Collected  
---|---  
When you sign-up to: receive free content, including eBooks, videos and offers;| Email address, First name , Last name  
When you purchase a book directly from us| Name, Email address, Phone number, Any Personal Data which you provide to us in the free text box of the form. Payment method choice (payment details are held by our payment processor, not us)  
When you complete the media enquiries form| Name, Email address, Phone number, Any Personal Data which you provide to us in the free text box of the form  
  
 _Data that we collect automatically_

I automatically collect certain information when you visit my Website – such as the type of browser and operating system you are using, and the domain name of your Internet service provider. I do not link this information with any Personal Data.

I may also collect data automatically through my use of cookies on the Website. Please see my cookie policy to find out about the types of cookies I set and why, and how you can adjust your settings to disable cookies.

2\. Use of your Personal Data

We will only use your Personal Data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we use your  
Personal Data to:

• process and manage your use of our website;  
• respond to your questions, comments and requests;  
• where you have opted-in to receive marketing from us, deliver communications that are  
relevant to your preferences / may be of interest to you;  
• improve our services and Website through analysis of information.

3\. Sharing of your Personal Data

We take your privacy seriously and will not share your Personal Data with others, except as permitted by applicable law or as set out below:

We share Personal Data as necessary with third parties who provide services or functions on our behalf and who require the information to provide those specific services to us. These third parties may include social media advertising platforms such as Facebook and Google Adwords for the purpose of custom audience generation and the development of targeting criteria for other audiences. Please note that we have appropriate data privacy safeguards in place with third parties with whom we share Personal Data as described above and who are providing services or functions on our behalf.

4\. Keeping your Personal Data secure

We have implemented security policies and technical measures to safeguard the Personal Data we collect. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable law, including the GDPR, to safeguard Personal Data from accidental loss, destruction or damage and unauthorised access, use and disclosure.

5\. Retention periods for use of your Personal Data

We will use and store your Personal Data only for as long as necessary, bearing in mind the uses of your Personal Data as described in this privacy policy and otherwise as communicated to you. We review the Personal Data we hold at regular intervals and delete permanently or anonymise any Personal Data which is no longer necessary.

6\. Children

This Website and our services are aimed at adults, and we do not knowingly collect any Personal Data relating to children aged under 15 years old. If you are under the age of 15, please do not provide us with any of your Personal Data, including your email address.

7\. Access to and control over your Personal Data

You have legal rights under applicable law in relation to your Personal Data. You can ask the following questions, or take the following actions, at any time by contacting us via email contact@novelexperience.info:  
• see what Personal Data we hold about you (if any), including why we are holding it and who it could be disclosed to;  
• ask us to change/correct your Personal Data;  
• ask us to delete your Personal Data;  
• object to the processing of your Personal Data;  
• ask us to restrict the processing of your Personal Data;

• withdraw any consents you have given us to the processing of your Personal Data; and  
• express any concerns you have about third parties’ use of your Personal Data.

8\. Change of purpose

We  will only use your Personal Data for the purposes for which we I collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to have an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.  
If we need to use your Personal Data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

9\. Contact Us

My full details are: Hazel Longuet  
Email for Privacy Questions: contact@novelexperience.info
